okay so this is what a rat looks like
it's a table where for each
architectural register for example for
r0 it will say where do we keep r0
currently then for R1 there is another
entry and so on so so this table really
just stores where things are this is
just for our convenience you know we
kind of Number the entries but basically
doesn't need to store this zero here
it's simply that the entry number Z is
for r0 the entry number one is for R1
Etc so now will have some instructions
let's first look at this first
instruction so let's say the processer
is fetching this instruction what it
does is for all the registers that this
instruction needs to read it looks in
the rat where those register can
currently be found let's say that for R2
this is just saying P2 for now so this
is physical register 2 which corresponds
to R2 initially and let's say that it's
P3 here in fact let's say that all of
them are just like this so what the
processor does does is it renames this
instruction so it fetches it decodes it
and then rewrites it so that the actual
operation that will be done is going to
be on physical registers P2 and P3 and
now the question is where are we going
to put our result well we're going to
put our result in a new place for R1 so
not in P1 so we will change the rat to
put the result in some p17 or whatever
okay so now we're going to say that this
is this out goes to p7 and then we're
going to use P2 and P3 for the inputs
let's say that the next instruction is
subtract R1 and R5 and put the result in
R4 what the processor again will do is
so it always follows the same procedure
look at the rat for R1 and R5 to see
where those values currently are and
then rename the so we're going to look
at R1 and it says p7 so this subtract is
renamed into read p7
and P5 and put the result into a new
place for R4 so we're going to change
the r from now on to put the result in
let's say
p8 okay so I've added three more
instructions and now we can rename them
to so this xor will be renamed into an
xor of R7 and R8 where are they well
let's say they're in p7 and p8 and then
we're going to write to R six we're not
going to write to P5 that's where the pr
previous value of R6 is we're going to
write it to a new register p19 then
we're going to take this multiply and
remember you need to update the rat
every time you produce a new value
because that's where subsequent
instructions will find the value for
that register so we're going to again R8
and R9 still not change so they're going
to be p8 and
P9 the new value for R5 is going to go
to P20 and then we have this add R8 and
and R9 are still in p8 and P9 the new
value of R4 is now going to be p21 now
this is an already renamed value so
we're going to rename it again and say
p21 later on if there is an instruction
that uses R4 so something something R4
it's going to be renamed into whatever
p21 so the trick here is that we have
seen that this instruction writes to R4
and this one also writes to R4 so there
is a register name dependence between
these two because they're both trying to
write to R4 but when we rename them this
way the dependence is gone because this
is producing p18 this is producing p21
instructions among these that need to
write the value so basically if
something here was reading R4 it would
get the value p18 instead because it's
been it would be renamed to read p8
anything that follows this instruction
that wants to read R4 would be renamed
so that it reads the p21 so simply the
use of R4 as a name for the value
produced by this instruction and also
for the value that produced by this
instruction is what was causing for
example the right after right dependence
we eliminate that dependence because
here the name will be different this
value is going to be named p18 this one
will be p21 there is no more dependence